<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rob Coleman</title>
    <link>https://robcoleman.ca/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Rob Coleman</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>coleman.rob&#43;nospam@gmail.com (Rob Coleman)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>coleman.rob&#43;nospam@gmail.com (Rob Coleman)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Nov 2018 22:13:15 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://robcoleman.ca/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on incentives in labour market programs</title>
      <link>https://robcoleman.ca/notes/almps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Nov 2018 22:13:15 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>coleman.rob&#43;nospam@gmail.com (Rob Coleman)</author>
      <guid>https://robcoleman.ca/notes/almps/</guid>
      <description>this research evaluates the strictness of rules (eligibility criteria) that govern the receipt of benefits (first-tier/unemployment and second-tier/welfare) across OECD countries they establish what types of eligibility criteria are common across countries they surveyed each OECD country and derived a quantitative policy indicator of eligibility strictness of each scheme they discuss the impacts of the eligibility choices on first and second tier benefits (for Canada, they used Ontario Works) and marginally discuss administrative provisions (how clients interact with administration)  Eligibility Criteria  entitlement conditions: these are the rules set by the feds over which Ontario has little influence (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer reading</title>
      <link>https://robcoleman.ca/post/summer_reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Sep 2018 17:25:23 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>coleman.rob&#43;nospam@gmail.com (Rob Coleman)</author>
      <guid>https://robcoleman.ca/post/summer_reading/</guid>
      <description>Robot Proof: Higher Education in the age of Artificial Intelligence
Joseph E. Anoun
 A short but well written glimpse into how higher ed will have to adapt given the progress of artificial intelligence and its impact on human work. Anoun mostly follows Harari on the transition of human work but is more an optimist insofar as he thinks there will still be a role for humans alongside machines in the labour market.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Open Data to map Bill 148 effects</title>
      <link>https://robcoleman.ca/post/writeup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>coleman.rob&#43;nospam@gmail.com (Rob Coleman)</author>
      <guid>https://robcoleman.ca/post/writeup/</guid>
      <description>I covered some interesting changes to minimum wage in my last post. I&amp;rsquo;m trying to build my skills in the mapping department, so I&amp;rsquo;m going to create an interactive map of the communities most affected by the change in minimum wage.
Loading the data The wage data is collected by the Canadian federal government and published as an open dataset available for download. The data is geographically organized by economic region, so we&amp;rsquo;ll need the shapefile for those boundaries which is also published as an open dataset!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minimum Wage Changes in Ontario</title>
      <link>https://robcoleman.ca/post/minwage/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2018 17:24:45 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>coleman.rob&#43;nospam@gmail.com (Rob Coleman)</author>
      <guid>https://robcoleman.ca/post/minwage/</guid>
      <description>Ontario has recently made changes to the minimum wage and many didn&amp;rsquo;t react calmly. I thought it might be interesting to see what kinds of occupations will be affected by the changes. Thankfully, the federal government posted a dataset on wages that helps answer some questions.
Exploring the data We can use the dataset to find out which occupations have a median wage of less than $14/hr. I&amp;rsquo;m particularly interested in my neck of the woods, Northern Ontario.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using R with Google BigQuery</title>
      <link>https://robcoleman.ca/post/bigquery/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Dec 2017 23:12:22 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>coleman.rob&#43;nospam@gmail.com (Rob Coleman)</author>
      <guid>https://robcoleman.ca/post/bigquery/</guid>
      <description>Google&amp;rsquo;s BigQuery has some interesting public datasets and luckily there&amp;rsquo;s an R package that makes interacting with the data extremely easy. The bigrquery library let&amp;rsquo;s you use SQL or dplyr statements to query the data which is super helpful.
Simple Query I took a look at the data from the US Census Bureau’s International dataset which provides projections on population indicators. You need to create a projectid in the bigquery interface before you start.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mapping 2016 Census Data</title>
      <link>https://robcoleman.ca/post/censusmap/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>coleman.rob&#43;nospam@gmail.com (Rob Coleman)</author>
      <guid>https://robcoleman.ca/post/censusmap/</guid>
      <description>The 2016 Census has a lot of useful data to be examined. Luckily, there&amp;rsquo;s a great R package cancensus that let&amp;rsquo;s you access and map the data easily.
You can use get_census to download the table and geographic features you need.
sault_income &amp;lt;- get_census(dataset=&amp;#39;CA16&amp;#39;, regions=list(CMA=&amp;#34;35590&amp;#34;), vectors=&amp;#34;v_CA16_2397&amp;#34;, level=&amp;#39;DA&amp;#39;, quiet = TRUE, geo_format = &amp;#39;sf&amp;#39;, labels = &amp;#39;short&amp;#39;) The dataframe is ready to be mapped using ggplot or leaflet if you want to be interactive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scraping Restaurant Health Inspections</title>
      <link>https://robcoleman.ca/post/resto/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2017 22:24:48 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>coleman.rob&#43;nospam@gmail.com (Rob Coleman)</author>
      <guid>https://robcoleman.ca/post/resto/</guid>
      <description>Algoma Public Health is the public health agency in my area that inspects restaurants to ensure they are abiding by all the relevant food safety legislation. They are also nice enough to publish their restaurant health inspection reports online for anyone to review.
I searched for a few restaurants that I frequent (phew Fratellis is safe!) but then I wanted to know which restaurants had the most health infractions?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using rvest to scrape National Occupation Codes</title>
      <link>https://robcoleman.ca/post/noc-noc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2017 11:01:19 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>coleman.rob&#43;nospam@gmail.com (Rob Coleman)</author>
      <guid>https://robcoleman.ca/post/noc-noc/</guid>
      <description>At work, I&amp;rsquo;m always looking for a list of National Occupation Codes and their descriptions. I realized I can probably scrape this information faster than I can find it on my team&amp;rsquo;s network drive thanks to rvest and the tidyverse.
Libraries:
library(tidyverse) # make tidy library(rvest) # scrape data library(knitr) # make a table Read in the appropriate list of NOCs:
nocs &amp;lt;- read_html(&amp;#34;http://noc.esdc.gc.ca/English/NOC/QuickSearch.aspx?ver=16&amp;amp;val65=*&amp;#34;) Parse the HTML into a list then a file:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://robcoleman.ca/page/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>coleman.rob&#43;nospam@gmail.com (Rob Coleman)</author>
      <guid>https://robcoleman.ca/page/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi, I&amp;rsquo;m Rob a government researcher in the field of employment and training. I studied political science and other fun subjects in school. Now I spend a lot of time analyzing data using #rstats and building things on the web.
I live in the frozen Canadian north with my partner and this guy:
  View this post on Instagram        Barn yard!
A post shared by Rob (@robcoleman) on Aug 24, 2017 at 3:04pm PDT</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>