<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Rob Coleman</title>
    <link>https://robcoleman.ca/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Rob Coleman</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://robcoleman.ca/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://robcoleman.ca/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robcoleman.ca/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi, I&amp;rsquo;m Rob 😄
I work in government at the intersection of data science and active labour market policy. I studied political science and economics. Now I spend a lot of time analyzing data using #rstats and building things on the web.
I live in the Canadian north with my partner and this guy:
   View this post on Instagram        Barn yard!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on employment barriers</title>
      <link>https://robcoleman.ca/notes/emp-barriers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robcoleman.ca/notes/emp-barriers/</guid>
      <description>Rodrigo Fernandezi, Herwig Immervolli, Daniele Pacificoi and Céline Thévenoti, 2016
 this research advances new methods to categorize employment barriers among jobseekers so as to design appropriately tailored activation responses across policy and institutional domains. little is known about specific employment barriers at the individual level, instead broad proxies are used to describe populations (NEET, older workers etc) instead the authors try a bottom up approach by categorizing and measuring employment barriers using latest class analysis (LDA), a clustering method, the authors find more useful groups of jobseekers who share common employment barriers by analyzing the European Union Statisitcs on Income and Living Conditions (EU SILC) available here  Types of Employment Barriers  lack of work-relateed capabilities  a range of factors that may limit an individuals&amp;rsquo; capacity to perform a specific task (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on Bayesian Statistics</title>
      <link>https://robcoleman.ca/books/bayes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2019 15:02:10 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robcoleman.ca/books/bayes/</guid>
      <description>Sources  Student&amp;rsquo;s Guide to Bayesian Statisitcs, Ben Lambert Statistical Rethinking, Richard McElreath Probability Theory: The Logic of Science, E.T. Jaynes  Part 1 Statistical Inference  sometimes we know the process that generates data (e.g. coin-flip) and so calculating probability is straightforward. when we don&amp;rsquo;t have perfect knowledge of the process; it is the goal of statistical inference to derive estimates of unknown characteristics or parameters of these data-generating mechanisms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Booklist &#43; ratings update</title>
      <link>https://robcoleman.ca/books/books/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robcoleman.ca/books/books/</guid>
      <description>2019    Title Author Rating     Measures of Success: React Less, Lead Better, Improve More Mark Graban ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️   Other Minds: The Octopus, the Sea, and the Deep Origins of Consciousness Peter Godfrey-Smith ⭐️⭐️⭐️   Bad Blood: Secrets and Lies in a Silicon Valley Startup John Carreyrou ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️   The Beginning of Infinity: Explanations That Transform the World David Deutsch ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️   Future Babble: Why Expert Predictions Fail - and Why We Believe Them Anyway Dan Gardner ⭐️⭐️   Better Now: Six Big Ideas to Improve Health Care for All Canadians Danielle Martin ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️   Just Mercy: A Story of Justice and Redemption Bryan Stevenson ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️   The Black Swan: The Impact of the Highly Improbable Nassim Nicholas Taleb ⭐️⭐️⭐️    2018    Title Author Rating     The Great Stagnation: How America Ate All the Low-Hanging Fruit of Modern History, Got Sick, and Will (Eventually) Feel Better Tyler Cowen ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️   Educated Tara Westover ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️   The Undoing Project: A Friendship That Changed Our Minds Michael Lewis ⭐️⭐️⭐️   Seven Fallen Feathers: Racism, Death, and Hard Truths in a Northern City Tanya Talaga ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️   Robot-Proof: Higher Education in the Age of Artificial Intelligence Joseph E.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing Commuting Patterns in Ontario</title>
      <link>https://robcoleman.ca/post/commute/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2019 10:16:59 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robcoleman.ca/post/commute/</guid>
      <description>I was inspired by David Robinson&amp;rsquo;s latest webcast in which he made a heatmap of French train delays using geom_tile and wanted to try it out for myself.
 In this week&amp;#39;s #tidytuesday screencast, I analyze delays in French train stations 🇫🇷🚄
I show how to create heatmaps of delays (inspired by @noccaea!), and embarrass myself with even the simplest French pronunciationshttps://t.co/zBrkIkdcCz #rstats pic.twitter.com/RI7ZpxV89X
&amp;mdash; David Robinson (@drob) February 26, 2019</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on Moral hazard</title>
      <link>https://robcoleman.ca/notes/moralhazard/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2019 17:52:48 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robcoleman.ca/notes/moralhazard/</guid>
      <description>Moral hazard in ALMPs Bruttel, Oliver 2005
 This research reviews the mechanisms by which government can manage the risks (moral hazard) associated with contracting out of ALMPs using a principal-agent theory lens. the author solves for the risks by advancing an integrated governance approach using 3 distinct governance mechanisms  incentives information control  reviews 3 countries (UK, Netherlands, Australia)  Principal-agent theory and moral hazard  concerned with how does govt (principal) ensure that service providers (agents) act in the govts interest main risk is moral hazard where agents act in their own interest (maximising utility, risk avoidance etc) where principal cannot observe their actions moral hazard in ALMPs revolve around 3 key areas:  creaming - selecting only optimal clients for service parking - not serving clients with low success probability dead-weight - serving clients who would have otherwise been successful without intervention (not explicitly mentioned but described elsewhere)   1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on outcomes in labour market programs</title>
      <link>https://robcoleman.ca/notes/whatworks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 15:50:35 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robcoleman.ca/notes/whatworks/</guid>
      <description>Estimating the Impact of Active Labour Market Programs using Administrative Data and Matching Methods Handouyahia, 2016
 research link using admin data matched to CRA they find that EBSMs have positive effects on employment and earnings  Findings  EBSMs caused gains in employment earnings, incidence of employment (+2.4% first year to +4.4% by fifth year) and reduction of EI benefits after completing SD had most pronounced effect (between $204 and $4,059 higher) SD represents the largest incremental gains  Labour market program efficacy: Evidence from Ontario Works Adams et.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on incentives in labour market programs</title>
      <link>https://robcoleman.ca/notes/almps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Nov 2018 22:13:15 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robcoleman.ca/notes/almps/</guid>
      <description>this research evaluates the strictness of rules (eligibility criteria) that govern the receipt of benefits (first-tier/unemployment and second-tier/welfare) across OECD countries they establish what types of eligibility criteria are common across countries they surveyed each OECD country and derived a quantitative policy indicator of eligibility strictness of each scheme they discuss the impacts of the eligibility choices on first and second tier benefits (for Canada, they used Ontario Works) and marginally discuss administrative provisions (how clients interact with administration)  Eligibility Criteria  entitlement conditions: these are the rules set by the feds over which Ontario has little influence (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer reading</title>
      <link>https://robcoleman.ca/books/summer_reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Sep 2018 17:25:23 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robcoleman.ca/books/summer_reading/</guid>
      <description>Robot Proof: Higher Education in the age of Artificial Intelligence
Joseph E. Anoun
 A short but well written glimpse into how higher ed will have to adapt given the progress of artificial intelligence and its impact on human work. Anoun mostly follows Harari on the transition of human work but is more an optimist insofar as he thinks there will still be a role for humans alongside machines in the labour market.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Open Data to map Bill 148 effects</title>
      <link>https://robcoleman.ca/post/writeup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robcoleman.ca/post/writeup/</guid>
      <description>I covered some interesting changes to minimum wage in my last post. I&amp;rsquo;m trying to build my skills in the mapping department, so I&amp;rsquo;m going to create an interactive map of the communities most affected by the change in minimum wage.
Loading the data The wage data is collected by the Canadian federal government and published as an open dataset available for download. The data is geographically organized by economic region, so we&amp;rsquo;ll need the shapefile for those boundaries which is also published as an open dataset!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minimum Wage Changes in Ontario</title>
      <link>https://robcoleman.ca/post/minwage/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2018 17:24:45 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robcoleman.ca/post/minwage/</guid>
      <description>Ontario has recently made changes to the minimum wage and many didn&amp;rsquo;t react calmly. I thought it might be interesting to see what kinds of occupations will be affected by the changes. Thankfully, the federal government posted a dataset on wages that helps answer some questions.
Exploring the data We can use the dataset to find out which occupations have a median wage of less than $14/hr. I&amp;rsquo;m particularly interested in my neck of the woods, Northern Ontario.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using R with Google BigQuery</title>
      <link>https://robcoleman.ca/post/bigquery/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Dec 2017 23:12:22 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robcoleman.ca/post/bigquery/</guid>
      <description>Google&amp;rsquo;s BigQuery has some interesting public datasets and luckily there&amp;rsquo;s an R package that makes interacting with the data extremely easy. The bigrquery library let&amp;rsquo;s you use SQL or dplyr statements to query the data which is super helpful.
Simple Query I took a look at the data from the US Census Bureau’s International dataset which provides projections on population indicators. You need to create a projectid in the bigquery interface before you start.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mapping 2016 Census Data</title>
      <link>https://robcoleman.ca/post/censusmap/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robcoleman.ca/post/censusmap/</guid>
      <description>The 2016 Census has a lot of useful data to be examined. Luckily, there&amp;rsquo;s a great R package cancensus that let&amp;rsquo;s you access and map the data easily.
You can use get_census to download the table and geographic features you need.
sault_income &amp;lt;- get_census(dataset=&amp;#39;CA16&amp;#39;, regions=list(CMA=&amp;#34;35590&amp;#34;), vectors=&amp;#34;v_CA16_2397&amp;#34;, level=&amp;#39;DA&amp;#39;, quiet = TRUE, geo_format = &amp;#39;sf&amp;#39;, labels = &amp;#39;short&amp;#39;) The dataframe is ready to be mapped using ggplot or leaflet if you want to be interactive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scraping Restaurant Health Inspections</title>
      <link>https://robcoleman.ca/post/resto/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2017 22:24:48 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robcoleman.ca/post/resto/</guid>
      <description>Algoma Public Health is the public health agency in my area that inspects restaurants to ensure they are abiding by all the relevant food safety legislation. They are also nice enough to publish their restaurant health inspection reports online for anyone to review.
I searched for a few restaurants that I frequent (phew Fratellis is safe!) but then I wanted to know which restaurants had the most health infractions?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using rvest to scrape National Occupation Codes</title>
      <link>https://robcoleman.ca/post/noc-noc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2017 11:01:19 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robcoleman.ca/post/noc-noc/</guid>
      <description>At work, I&amp;rsquo;m always looking for a list of National Occupation Codes and their descriptions. I realized I can probably scrape this information faster than I can find it on my team&amp;rsquo;s network drive thanks to rvest and the tidyverse.
Libraries:
library(tidyverse) # make tidy library(rvest) # scrape data library(knitr) # make a table Read in the appropriate list of NOCs:
nocs &amp;lt;- read_html(&amp;#34;http://noc.esdc.gc.ca/English/NOC/QuickSearch.aspx?ver=16&amp;amp;val65=*&amp;#34;) Parse the HTML into a list then a file:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Search</title>
      <link>https://robcoleman.ca/search/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robcoleman.ca/search/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>