<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rob Coleman</title>
    <link>https://robcoleman.ca/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Rob Coleman</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2017 Rob Coleman</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://robcoleman.ca/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Mapping 2016 Census Data</title>
      <link>https://robcoleman.ca/blog/mapping-2016-census-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robcoleman.ca/blog/mapping-2016-census-data/</guid>
      <description>The 2016 Census has a lot of useful data to be examined. Luckily, there&amp;rsquo;s a great R package cancensus that let&amp;rsquo;s you access and map the data easily.
You can use get_census to download the table and geographic features you need.
sault_income &amp;lt;- get_census(dataset=&#39;CA16&#39;, regions=list(CMA=&amp;quot;35590&amp;quot;), vectors=&amp;quot;v_CA16_2397&amp;quot;, level=&#39;DA&#39;, quiet = TRUE, geo_format = &#39;sf&#39;, labels = &#39;short&#39;)  The dataframe is ready to be mapped using ggplot or leaflet if you want to be interactive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scraping Restaurant Health Inspections</title>
      <link>https://robcoleman.ca/blog/scraping-restaurant-health-inspections/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2017 22:24:48 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robcoleman.ca/blog/scraping-restaurant-health-inspections/</guid>
      <description>Algoma Public Health is the public health agency in my area that inspects restaurants to ensure they are abiding by all the relevant food safety legislation. They are also nice enough to publish their restaurant health inspection reports online for anyone to review.
I searched for a few restaurants that I frequent (phew Fratellis is safe!) but then I wanted to know which restaurants had the most health infractions?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using rvest to scrape National Occupation Codes</title>
      <link>https://robcoleman.ca/blog/using-rvest-to-scrape-national-occupation-codes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2017 11:01:19 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robcoleman.ca/blog/using-rvest-to-scrape-national-occupation-codes/</guid>
      <description>At work, I&amp;rsquo;m always looking for a list of National Occupation Codes and their descriptions. I realized I can probably scrape this information faster than I can find it on my team&amp;rsquo;s network drive thanks to rvest and the tidyverse.
Libraries:
library(tidyverse) # make tidy library(rvest) # scrape data library(knitr) # make a table  Read in the appropriate list of NOCs:
nocs &amp;lt;- read_html(&amp;quot;http://noc.esdc.gc.ca/English/NOC/QuickSearch.aspx?ver=16&amp;amp;val65=*&amp;quot;)  Parse the HTML into a list then a file:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://robcoleman.ca/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robcoleman.ca/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi, I&amp;rsquo;m Rob a government researcher in the field of employment and training.
I studied political science and other fun subjects in school. Now I spend a lot of time analyzing data using #rstats and building things on the web.
I live in the frozen Canadian north with my wife and this guy:
 Barn yard!
A post shared by Rob (@robcoleman) on Aug 24, 2017 at 3:04pm PDT
  Let&amp;rsquo;s be friends!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Home</title>
      <link>https://robcoleman.ca/home/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robcoleman.ca/home/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>License</title>
      <link>https://robcoleman.ca/license/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robcoleman.ca/license/</guid>
      <description>You can use this page to put a license on the contents of your blog, like so:
 The MIT License (MIT)
Copyright &amp;copy; 2015 Nishanth Shanmughamnishanth.gerrard@gmail.com
Permission is hereby granted, free of charge, to any person obtaining a copy of this software and associated documentation files (the &amp;ldquo;Software&amp;rdquo;), to deal in the Software without restriction, including without limitation the rights to use, copy, modify, merge, publish, distribute, sublicense, and/or sell copies of the Software, and to permit persons to whom the Software is furnished to do so, subject to the following conditions:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>